<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notes on</title><link>https://emilyyao.me/notes/</link><description>Recent content in Notes on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://emilyyao.me/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CS 220</title><link>https://emilyyao.me/notes/cs220/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://emilyyao.me/notes/cs220/</guid><description>Self-paced course taken summer &amp;lsquo;22, linked here. Introductory data science programming using Python &amp;ndash; teaches Python basics, programming fundamentals, and data science modules in Python.</description></item><item><title>CS 544</title><link>https://emilyyao.me/notes/cs544/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://emilyyao.me/notes/cs544/</guid><description>resources &amp;amp; deployment intro Big 3 categories of software: Analysis code &amp;ndash; running Python code once on some data to get results Application &amp;ndash; continuously running the code, like a website Systems &amp;ndash; how to manage resources such as storage space Systems resources: compute -&amp;gt; CPU, GPU CPUs can each have multiple cores, which can be independently executing &amp;ldquo;core code&amp;rdquo; (machine code) More cores means that more tasks can be run simultaneously High level code -&amp;gt; compiled to bytecode -&amp;gt; ran by a VM -&amp;gt; VM is running on a core GPU has many cores that are coordinated and slow because they have to run together Cost measurement: FLOPS (floating-point operations per second) mem -&amp;gt; RAM RAM stores bits Small, volatile (lost upon reboot) and fast storage -&amp;gt; HDD, SSD Data read/written in blocks of many bytes/blocks Large, nonvolatile, slow How fast can be read/write data?</description></item><item><title>CS 61A</title><link>https://emilyyao.me/notes/cs61a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://emilyyao.me/notes/cs61a/</guid><description>Self-paced course taken summer &amp;lsquo;22, linked here. Beginner programming course using Python &amp;ndash; teaches data abstraction, &amp;hellip; Great focus on shortcuts and problem-solving with code; has hints of competitive coding strategies.</description></item></channel></rss>